Dr. Khalifa: Innovations creep up on us, and after one generation or two generations, there will be parts.
Parts will be added to the prayer.
When you're by yourself, wonderful, make Tasbih, and Zikr, and Sujoods, and anything you want to do.
But when we're a group, like, you saw that I really go to unusual lengths to... immediately, I say "Al-Salaamu ‘Alaykum" and say "congratulations."
When I'm by myself, I make Du'a and Tasbih and extra Sujoods or whatever I want to do, whatever I feel like.
And it is not a set thing.
No, you don't count, no.
You make Tasbih, it doesn't count. That will distract you.
But I don't know if it's an Iranian habit to make a Sujood after the Salam or what. Do you always do that? Everybody does that?
Dr. Khalifa: Almost. A woman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: After, after you say "Al-Salaamu ‘Alaykum, Al-Salaamu ‘Alaykum", or after you finish the Salam, everybody makes Sujud?
See, it became part of the Salat in Iran.
And this, they may bring it to us.
This will cause the number of Sujuds to be numerically unbalanced, numerically wrong.
Not that you can't do it by yourself. When you're by yourself, you do do it and you feel like falling prostrate, do it.
But it becomes part and parcel of the prayer, and then, you don't have four Sujuds.
In the morning, we did four Sujuds.
Because God is so great, if you are in Sujud from birth to death, that is not sufficient to really express our devotion to God.
Therefore, it is a numerical structure.
It's a symbolic thing. So, two more Sujuds will not do anything as far as expressing our servitude to God.
So, everything is numerical in the prayer, the Ruku's, the Sujuds, letters, words.
Let's, when we are in public, let us just stick to the prayer. Otherwise, before you know it, it will be parts added to the Salat.
And believe me, I resist making prayers and things, Du'a, just because of that point, when we are in public.
If I make prayers, it will take only a short time and then everybody after Salam will go and make prayers and so on.
And then, it will become part and parcel at that day.
Page 418.
In the name of God, Most Gracious, Most Merciful
[33:1] O you prophet, observe GOD and do not obey the disbelievers and hypocrites. GOD is Omniscient, Most Wise.
I'm gonna stop right here.
This is to the prophet Muhammad.
He was the last prophet.
And God uses him as an example for the rest of us.
Observe God, (33:1) ٱتَّقِ ٱللَّهَ Be righteous, be conscious of God.
It doesn't mean that he was not, but it's a commandment for him and for us to observe God in everything we do, everything we say.
[33:1] ... do not obey the disbelievers and hypocrites. ...
The disbelievers and hypocrites, when they give up on you and they find that your argument is very strong
and unbeatable in the Quran, they tell you "you worship Rashad Khalifa, or you follow Rashad Khalifa."
They play with your last god, which is ego.
So, "do not obey the disbelievers and hypocrites" because they are the ones who will utter that statement.
When a person utters that statement, they know full well we worship God alone
and we do not follow Rashad Khalifa or worship Rashad Khalifa. We follow what God says.
Rashad Khalifa says anything that's not in the Quran, you will be the first to tell him "this is not in the Quran, why do you say that?"
And it is your duty not to obey me if it is not in the Quran.
And as a matter of fact, in this Sura, it says do not follow the Prophet Muhammad,
we're talking about the Prophet, so do not obey him if he's saying something that is not righteous,
something that is not in Quran, in other words.
I forget which verse it is, but we will come to it today.
[33:1] ... do not obey the disbelievers and hypocrites. ...
When they tell you, you follow Rashad Khalifa, you just look at them and smile because this reveals their stupidity.
We are going out of our way to destroy idols, not to make idols.
Our only god is God.
And we have reached the conviction in our hearts that God alone possesses all power.
We reached the conviction in our hearts that no saint, no prophet, no Muhammad, no Jesus,
no Rashad Khalifa, no anybody, no one other than God can guide us.
I think, I think that was a good demonstration at the conference that I see people whom I love fall by the wayside.
Obviously, I can't do anything to help them because it is between them and God.
If they don't have the conviction in their hearts, there is nothing in the world they can do or anybody else can do to save them.
And God gave examples in the Quran, Noah's son. Does Noah love his son?
Noah, one of the great Prophets, couldn't help him.
Abraham, how about Abraham? How close is Abraham to God?
As close as can be, right?
I mean, if anyone gets very close to God, it will be probably as close as Abraham.
I don't wanna make it a rule, you may be closer than Abraham to God.
We have to hold out that possibility.
But Abraham's father is going to Hell, and God reprimanded Abraham for asking forgiveness for his father.
God loves Abraham very much.
Abraham asked God to forgive his father, but God reprimanded Abraham.
So, we are people who know full well that no human being, certainly not Rashad Khalifa, can help you
in anything, except give you the message, do this with you, discuss it with you. This is all we can do.
Therefore, there is no idol worship.
Therefore, when they tell you "you worship Rashad Khalifa", you smile at them.
They are not even worth one second of your time.
[33:1] O you prophet, observe GOD and do not obey the disbelievers and hypocrites. GOD is Omniscient, Most Wise.
What does "God is omniscient" mean?
In Arabic, 'Alim (عَلِيم).
If you read the Arabic, you see it there, (33:1) عَلِيمًا حَكِيمًۭا
This means God knows what's in your heart.
They may say "you worship Rashad Khalifa", but God knows that in your heart, you don't.
We love each other a lot, but that is not idol worship.
We love each other because God made it the law that we are a family.
Sura 49.
(49:10) إِنَّمَا ٱلْمُؤْمِنُونَ إِخْوَةٌۭ The believers are brothers and sisters.
Brothers and sisters for eternity love each other.
Now, don't confuse this with idol worship.
Idol worship is simply knowing that this person can help you, help, guide you, or help your, help your health
or help in any other way, other than share the message with you.
[33:1] ... GOD is Omniscient, Most Wise.
[33:2] Follow what is revealed to you from your Lord. ...
Straightforward, clear?
This is what we follow. We do not follow Muhammad or Jesus or any human being.
So, when they try to poke your ego and say "you follow this or that", you don't, it doesn't bother you.
Because God knows that we don't follow any human being.
We follow what God... We follow what is revealed to us from our Lord.
[33:2] Follow what is revealed to you from your Lord. GOD is fully Cognizant of everything you all do.
A man: A question.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, sir.
A man: You said "we follow what's revealed to you from your Lord."
A man: Of course, we would not follow the human messenger that you just mentioned. Dr. Khalifa: Exactly.
A man: That reference to the previous scriptures recorded and defaced as they've been.
A man: This would also prove them apprehending to learn our Quran. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: Because this, the (unintelligible) for. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: So, this entails that... (unintelligible) that we can
A man: read all these previous scriptures, the book of the Jews, Christians (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Because God's truth is there.
A man: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: God's truth is there and is beautiful.
And the human injections are very obvious.
You have (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: This is very clear.
A man: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Dr. Khalifa: Using the Quran as a criteria.
The Quran is the ultimate reference.
Sura 5, verse 48.
If it contradicts the Quran, it doesn't appeal with the Quran, then it is out.
The last few days, we talked about Abraham's courage versus the Bible's Abraham's cowardice.
So, it's obvious. If the Quran tells us Ibrahim was courageous, then Ibrahim was courageous.
That's just one example.
[33:2] Follow what is revealed to you from your Lord. GOD is fully Cognizant of everything you all do.
[33:3] You shall put your trust in GOD. GOD suffices as an advocate.
You don't want to appease any human beings.
When they tell you "you follow Rashad Khalifa or you idol worship Rashad Khalifa", and it bothers you, then you have an ego.
Because you worry what the people are saying.
We don't give a damn what the people are saying. We know what we're doing. We know what we believe.
And it doesn't bother us what the people think of us. You will never please the people.
Anyway.
They are very jealous of you. Sura 2 says, they are very jealous of you. They want you to be a disbeliever like they are.
So, you be equal.
You know, ironically, they know you're on the right path. They know.
You're telling them "La Elaha Ella Allah."
But they can't overcome their god, their ego, to agree with you.
It's arrogance and ignorance that is keeping them.
Arrogance that they are jealous of you.
They don't wanna agree with you because it hurts their ego.
And it's ignorance because they don't realize that they should kill their ego in order to save their soul.
In order to go save themselves, their own necks.
Oh, he's going in the corner.
Now, before verse 4, we have a subtitle saying, "Devotion to God Is Indivisible."
[33:4] GOD did not give any man two hearts. Nor did He turn your wives whom you estrange (according to your custom) into your mothers.* Nor did He turn your adopted children into genetic offspring. All these are mere utterances that you have invented. GOD speaks the truth, and He guides in the (right) path.
We have several things in this verse.
First of all, our devotion must be to God alone.
You don't have two hearts in your chest.
Your heart belongs to God.
And there's a very good expression in Luke 12:29.
Luke 12:29, make a note of it.
It says "Seek God's kingship over you and everything else follows."
So, when you give your heart to God, your spouse will love you,
for example. Do you see the connection?
Everything else. Your boss will love you.
Everything else will be at your disposal.
We're going to stop this.
Luke 12:28, we're gonna start with that.
It says "If God clothes in such splendor the grass of the field, which grows today
"and is thrown on the fire tomorrow, how much more will He provide for you, O weak in faith?"
29, "it is not for you to be in search of what you are to eat or drink..."
And listen to this sentence "Stop worrying." It's two words.
"Stop worrying."
30, "the unbelievers of this world are always running after these things.
"Your father", should be your God, "knows that you need such things."
"Seek out instead His kingship over you and the rest will follow in turn."
You don't need to worry about provisions or jobs or anything. In your life, God must be the only priority.
Your work, your day is scheduled around the Five Prayers, not the other way around.
People say "I can't do the Noon Prayer because I'm busy doing this and that."
They should say that, I can't do my work because I'm doing the Noon Prayer.
What do you think?
When the Bible says what?
No, it is not... it's a misunderstanding of the languages.
Because Rabbi (رَبِّ) and rabbi, they confuse Rabb, the Lord, and rabb means father.
I don't know how it is in Iran, but in Arabic, the head of the family is called rabbi Al-Usra.
So, but, so, they can confuse that.
If they look at it, they say "the god of the family."
But it is not the god of the family. It's the head of the family.
I don't know if you use that... do you use that expression in Iran, the head of the family is rabb or lord?
No? Good.
We have that in Arabic and we have it even in the Quran, in Sura 12, where Yusuf
tells the man "Go to your lord", meaning your boss, and used the word "rabbika" (رَبِّكَ).
He said "Go to rabbika, your lord, your rabb, and tell him to get me out of here."
And other examples. So, when it says "your Father", it's a wrong expression.
It should be "your God."
So, you give your heart to God and everything else will be yours.
And then, the next instruction in verse 4 talks about estranging the wife, so she is hanging,
neither free to marry somebody else, nor enjoying the full rights of a wife.
God is very strong on the side of the wife.
Sura number 4, all has to do with the rights of women, because they have been oppressed all the time.
It is a tremendous test for us, men, and millions of men are falling into it.
So, we really have to bend backward and go out of our way to remove that oppression or any hint of it.
We are stronger physically. We are the bread earners. And we tend sometimes to tyrannize them without even feeling it.
So, we have to watch for this.
God is on the side of the oppressed, and He is very harsh with the oppressors.
Mercy and kindness are grace that God wants us to observe.
So, for our own neck, we have to go out of our way to be really kind and considerate of our spouses.
We don't wanna take them for granted, and we don't want to inflict any mental persecution on them, or physical, of course.
Dr. Khalifa: Go on.
A woman: It does mean also that God does not keep any man too hard with one wife.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. No, this has to do with devotion.
This has to do with the wife, the business, things of this world.
This means... This is the first commandment.
You must love God, your Lord, with all your heart, with all your body, all your soul, all your strength.
This is what it is. It has nothing to do with polygamy. No.
And then the other idea, in the same verse, is you adopt a child and give him your name.
Wrong.
It says "you adopt the children, who are not your genetic children.
You must preserve their lineage.
The name you have in your birth certificate is the name God gave you. It is David Flynn.
It's not really Davoud.
God gave you the name David Flynn.
So, when Islam came to this country, or when some people in this country came to Islam,
the Arabs took advantage of it and they gave them Arab names.
Those are not Muslim names.
You can find a counterpart in the Arab world who is the worst creature on earth with the same name as yours.
It has nothing to do with Islam.
I can show you a Sayyid Ahmad who was the worst woman on earth back then.
A man: Brother Rashad Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: What happens in situations (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Fine. That's Ok. That's Ok.
Dr. Khalifa: In fact, this is the way it's supposed to be.
A man: I mean for the child.
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, for the child. Say it again. So, give me a specific example.
A man: A man and a woman have a conflict and they break up.
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, oh.
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: OK. See, if the child's lineage is known, if the child's father is known, you give the child the name of the father, the real father.
Regardless of if he's with the man or the woman after divorce or before divorce, or when.
But if the child's lineage is not known, then you can give him your name if you want to. It's gonna come up here.
It's coming up in verse 5.
Do Not Change Your Names
[33:5] You shall give your adopted children names that preserve their relationship to their genetic fathers. This is more equitable in the sight of GOD. If you do not know their fathers, then, as your brethren in religion, you shall treat them as members of your family. You do not commit a sin if you make a mistake in this respect; you are only responsible for your actual intentions. GOD is Forgiver, Most Merciful.
I'm telling you, we are very guided people, Alhamdu Lillah, by God's grace.
I mean, we are enjoying God's guidance because we have living examples that teach us.
When I first... I was talking about this 10 years ago.
And I think part of you remember that I theorized that, theoretically, a brother and sister can marry each other because of this change of names.
They don't have their common last name.
Because they were adopted, this girl went to this family, and this boy went to this family, and they have now their family's names,
their adopted names.
Then, they grow up, they go to college, they meet each other, and they fall in love, and they marry.
This is a brother and sister marrying each other because they don't have their names.
You know something, this actually happened.
And one of the people that came to the conference, I don't know if she wants me to
say this or not, but her sister married her brother.
They actually got married.
I mean, how rare can this be? What's the chance?
I was saying it as a theory, maybe one in a million.
But turns out that it actually happened. I don't think she minds, but it's Mouvelle.
Remember Mouvelle (unintelligible)?
One of her sisters married one of her brothers.
And they found out, they broke up the marriage.
Yeah. They found out, and they immediately separated, heartbroken and everything.
But her sister met somebody in the market, I believe another sister, who knows the brother.
She said "I haven't seen you in a couple of years, how are you doing?"
I said "oh, I got married, and this and that", and updated the information.
And then, when she saw the husband, she said, "oh my gosh, this is our brother."
Because this is a sister that she knows, and "this is my brother." And it was, that was quite a shock.
And it's because of the changing of names.
Now, if they had the same names, if Rashad Khalifa meets Safiya Khalifa, we'll say "wait a minute, you may be my sister."
Dr. Khalifa: And we investigate.
A man: So then, the offspring should have the father's name? Yes, it should have father's name.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, should have the father's name, if the father is known.
I think the commandment is very clear.
And it's, it's difficult.
You know, Chester for a long time, he's been known as Khalifa. He got used to the name. It's not easy to give up a thing like this.
It's been my experience. Douglas Brown, it took me three years to talk him out of his name.
Dr. Khalifa: And I was, I'm laughing because he had a lot of pain that snapped him out of that name one time.
A man: She was quite sure that the father that (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, the connection was unmistakable. A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, did he tell you?
A man: Well, he told her in more detail. (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Right, okay.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, the connection was very strong.
For example, the day before, I told him straight forward, I said "Douglas, you have to change your name."
Of course, I force the name on them. I call you "Chester."
Chester: No, I'm laughing because you (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Chester: Because that's... Because it's not only (unintelligible) also.
Chester: I think, it's, it is there also. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Chester: From the very beginning, it wasn't imposed on me. Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Chester: Calling out my name. Because right from the very (unintelligible)
Chester: first meeting near the New York (unintelligible) in New York Island, they found out my name. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible) Chester: First of all, to tell them, you know, the day after they called me "Chester, Chester."
Dr. Khalifa: Wonderful, wonderful.
Dr. Khalifa: This helps you. Chester: Brother, brother, (unintelligible) you know, I take it all in stride.
Chester: At one time, I sort of resented it, but for the most part I took it in stride. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Chester: And it's becoming more now palatable.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Because we insist on calling you "Chester", sir.
Dr. Khalifa: After a while you have no choice.
Chester: Yes, yes, yes.
Dr. Khalifa: You get used, you know, you get used to the name.
Chester: (unintelligible) So, (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: God rewards you for it, because what you're doing, you're giving up your personal desires for what God is saying.
Dr. Khalifa: We all, we all do that. Chester: That's (unintelligible).
A woman: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Right. What happened?
Dr. Khalifa: They tell you, ask you "what happened?"
A woman: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Chester: What I'm looking at also is my family, my brothers and sisters, my mother, and my relatives and so forth.
Because they're saying "well, it must be very awful because you're changing your name."
Chester: "First of all, to an Arabic name, you didn't wanna change back. And then, it's fine." Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Chester: "What's the problem? What's wrong with that?" Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Dr. Khalifa: You tell them. You tell them "I found out that God says."
Dr. Khalifa: Iman.
Dr. Khalifa: That used to be her.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Iman: And at work, I had the same problem working, and it gave me an opportunity to engage with them.
You know, I always, I've been told I had to change my name.
And I did it because I was told I had to. But some of them has not necessarily.
Iman: They were told to keep their name.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Iman: But it was, it was a lot of conversation that made me realize (unintelligible).
Iman: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: The change is in your soul, and in your heart, the invisible part. It's not in the visible part.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: No, let's take, let's take Douglas Brown, for example.
Dr. Khalifa: There's, there's a Douglas Brown senior who raised Douglas Brown Jr., for example.
And it was heartbreaking for them, for Douglas Brown senior, to find that his son is now Rashid Hamid.
There's no connection with him whatsoever.
So, when Douglas changed back to his name, they were very happy, the parents were very happy, because they gained their son back.
There's some kind of, shall I use the word, pride, in raising your children and having them named after you.
It is not fair to the parents to strip them of that.
My father is Abdulhalim Khalifa, and I'm Rashad Khalifa, and he's kind of proud that
you know, "I raised this son."
Then all of a sudden, I am Ali Ahmed.
So,...
Yes, even the women, when they get married, should keep their names.
But, here in this country, I don't know, there's some inconveniences that go along with that, the checking accounts, the,
I don't know, the civil laws.
Feroz: People say they want a certain wife (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yes. That's right.
Feroz: (unintelligible) married and live on it. For additional security or something, they may be living together. Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Dr. Khalifa: See, once they're married, I mean, this is common sense now.
Because of the laws here, again, this will fall under the part of the Quran that says,
"if you're forced by circumstances, without being malicious or deliberate, then you are not committing a sin."
So, I will go along with changing the wife's name, if she so wills.
A compromise would be to keep the name of the family, and the husband's family.
For example, Batool's last name was what? Maiden name?
Huh?
Is this why you laugh?
Sajjadina? Sajjadina.
Okay, so it would be Batool Sajjadina Karmally.
Dr. Khalifa: That will be the compromise.
Feroz: So, it will be father's name?
Dr. Khalifa: Well, you guys in India and Pakistan don't have last names.
You don't have last names.
Dr. Khalifa: Really?
Feroz: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: I had a friend from Pakistan. His name was Salahuddin.
I say "Salahuddin in Egypt, it's the first name, it's one name."
So, Salahuddin, I say "what's your last name?" He says "Salahuddin."
"So, what's your first name?" "Salahuddin."
"Wait a minute."
I say, I said "Salahuddin is your name, right? What's your last name?"
He said "this is it. We don't have last names."
Apparently, it's very common in Pakistan.
Feroz: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: It is.
A woman: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Feroz: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: No, Mohammad Sharif.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. But then all of them, all of them are Mohammads.
A woman: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Mohammad Rafiq. So,...
Dr. Khalifa: But it's really his first name. He's Pakistani, right?
See? You don't have last names.
So, it all depends on the countries.
A man: (unintelligible) region. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. A man: Those who come from Punjab. Dr. Khalifa: I don't know.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. It's very possible. A man: (unintelligible)
A man: west Punjab and east Punjab
A man: (unintelligible)
A man: And those in east Punjab, they practice (unintelligible). The people who live in (unintelligible).
A man: Even though they are not Sikhs, they do not use the third name.
A man: And I don't, or if they do, then they don't use (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: So, it depends on the region, then.
Dr. Khalifa: This is true all over the world, but when we conform to God's law, it's just (unintelligible) understanding.
You have to remember not being malicious or deliberate. You're not being malicious or deliberate.
These two things must be there to qualify for permission.
[33:6] The prophet is closer to the believers than they are to each other, and his wives are like their mothers. Those who are related to each other shall take care of one another in accordance with GOD's scripture. Thus, the believers shall take care of their relatives who immigrate to them, provided they have taken care of their own families first. These are commandments of this scripture.
Anytime you see the word Prophet, in Arabic Nabi (نَّبِى), it has to do with the local incidents
involving the prophet Muhammad when he was alive.
But you can use, always use that as an example. This is what...They are the Quran. The Quran is for all times.
So, the prophet is closer to the believers than they are to each other,
because the prophet is receiving the Quran and delivering God's commandments to the people, which have to do with eternal existence.
Our physical relatives are our relatives in this temporary life.
If they become believers, they become our eternal family.
Another factor enters the picture.
I wanna go to the next verse, which is very important.
It has to do with the covenant that the prophets made.
Because in the September issue of 88 Perspective, they published an article, somebody was saying
that Muhammad was the messenger of the covenant. Which is very wrong.
Because God said, 3:81, God said "He made a covenant with the prophets."
Since Muhammad was the last prophet, therefore he was included.
God didn't say He made a covenant with the previous prophets or the prophets before Muhammad.
He said He made a covenant with the prophets that a messenger will come after them to unify their message.
Therefore, Muhammad is not that messenger.
The messenger comes after Muhammad.
But they established this lie that Muhammad is the last messenger, and they stick to it without any basis whatsoever. They have no basis.
So, God wills to put in 33:7, Sura 33, which is the other end of the Quran practically,
that Muhammad was one of the prophets involved in that covenant.
So, let us read number 7. It says,
[33:7] Recall that we took from the prophets their covenant,...
indicating it is one covenant. Because they will also try very hard to go to Hell and tell you "there were more than one covenant."
There wasn't. It was just one covenant.
[33:7] ... including a pledge from you (O Muhammad), and from Noah, Abraham, Moses, and Jesus the son of Mary. We took from them a solemn pledge.*
And you notice everyone, every name mentioned here is a prophet.
Because they were messengers who did not deliver scriptures like Saleh, Hud, Lot.
You don't see Lot here, or Saleh, or Hud.
So, these are prophets who brought scriptures.
Yeah, he brought the Gospel.
Yes.
That was not an out-of-body experience.
Dr. Khalifa: I had an out-of-body experience that I did deliberately. It was beautiful.
A man: (unintelligible) electric.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, anybody can do it.
A man: Really? Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: It's the nature of things.
Dr. Khalifa: That was, I was taken up to somewhere in the universe.
Dr. Khalifa: No, just the prophets.
Feroz: I'm just wondering, like, in the universe, the body goes, isn't there a lot of forces that can affect the body?
Feroz: Wouldn't it be easier and faster for the soul to go? Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, do you think if God wants to talk to Feroz Karmally and wants the person Feroz, do you think He can take care of the body? Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: You're right. There are forces, but at that time, remember, all of us have guards.
Feroz: But wasn't your body just lying down there?
Dr. Khalifa: I was just lying in bed with the radio on my chest, listening to the Cairo.
Feroz: So, your body then didn't go up, right?
Dr. Khalifa: Of course not. Feroz: Ok.
Dr. Khalifa: It can't be.
Feroz: It's just the soul went up. Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, the body cannot go up there.
Feroz: OK, that's what I was saying. Dr. Khalifa: There's no way.
Dr. Khalifa: First of all, the body needs oxygen.
Feroz: That's what I mean, Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: And the minute you go up 1,000, 50,000 feet, there's no oxygen.
Feroz: Isn't that really an out-of-body experience with regard to your body?
Dr. Khalifa: In a sense, yes. I mean, I'm amazed at the way Batool said it.
Dr. Khalifa: When you think about it, it really is an out-of-body experience. But it's a deliberate trance travel. A man: In other words, you didn't...
A man: you didn't deliberately, you didn't deliberately have the out-of-body experience. It was just that stuff.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, I was summoned.
Dr. Khalifa: We use the word "summon."
A man: Now, she asked a question. (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, I saw them all.
I was told after the announcement that your experience in Mecca was, that was fulfillment of the covenant of all the prophets.
I was told then that those are all the prophets.
When I came back, I told my father "guess what? I just met all the prophets."
And he said "how?" And I explained to him what I explained to you yesterday.
I told him exactly what I saw.
A man: (unintelligible) thousands of...
Feroz: No, it's a Hadith, 120 thousand prophets. Dr. Khalifa: No, no.
Feroz: I think all the prophets are mentioned in the Quran, are they not?
Dr. Khalifa: No.
Feroz: Not all the prophets? Because all the messengers are not, I know. A man: No.
Dr. Khalifa: However, God says "messengers."
However, some of these messengers may have been prophets. I don't know.
It says "Messengers that we told you about, messengers that we never told you about."
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Feroz: How many approximately did you see? Do you know?
Dr. Khalifa: I'd say 20, between 20 and 30.
Feroz: And how many are in the Quran?
Dr. Khalifa: About 18, 19.
Feroz: There may have been a few more.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. The prophet brings a new scripture, a new message.
A messenger confirms existing scriptures, preaches existing scriptures. He does not bring anything new.
Every prophet brings a new scripture.
We're using the word prophet for the Arabic word Nabi (نَّبِى).
Because the English usage of the word prophet is not the same as Nabi (نَّبِى).
This, what, 6:30? Is it 6:30?
Do you wanna have some breakfast before you go? Some cereal or something?
Dr. Khalifa: I know.
Feroz: Scripture doesn't have to be a book.
Dr. Khalifa: No, the word scripture, for example, Abraham's scripture is all practical.
Feroz: Because the word Kitab, the word Kitab means book, right?
Dr. Khalifa: I know.
Feroz: The word Kitab means book.
Dr. Khalifa: Scripture, yes. Feroz: Book scripture.
Dr. Khalifa: Script is writing.
So, the word scripture is not really accurate.
Message would be a more appropriate word, don't you think, Chester?
Chester: Message for the word? Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: For example, Abraham brought to us the Salat prayer, the Zakat charity, the fasting of Ramadan.
They're all practical things that were not written down.
What do you call that? What did Abraham receive?
Dr. Khalifa: If you say scripture, script means writing. There was nothing written.
A man: Scripture would entail more a body of writing. A body of writing. Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Dr. Khalifa: Which Abraham did not receive.
A man: Ok. And script itself would be a page of writing. Dr. Khalifa: Right.
A man: One individual document or something of that nature. Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Dr. Khalifa: So, what would be the best word to express what Abraham was given?
Something that God gave him to deliver to us.
Dr. Khalifa: And it is all practices of... How about...
A man: Instructions?
Dr. Khalifa: From God message, a message.
Dr. Khalifa: Like a message from God.
Dr. Khalifa: Anyway, we understand what it is, but we call it scripture.
Because the word scripture has to do with the holy revelations from God.
So, when they argue with you and say "Muhammad was not one of those prophets", you show them 33:7.
Which is what I did in the Perspective. I gave them the answer. And I tell you, I haven't heard a word from them since then.
It's been a year plus.
It's been one year and two months, I haven't heard a single word. They were really belligerent.
Dr. Khalifa: This is the Muslim Digest magazine in South Africa, in South Africa.
Ahmad: written by Dr. Khalifa: An Indian.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. Not a word, Ahmad
Dr. Khalifa: He said nothing. Because what can they say?
The evidence is very clear. There is nothing you can say. Muhammad is one of the prophets who made the covenant.
Therefore, the messenger who comes after the prophet must be separate from Muhammad.
Dr. Khalifa: True.
Ahmad: Perhaps you may like to consider this in your next issue.
Ahmad: (unintelligible)
Ahmad: Now, I have... somebody sent me a book explaining, you know, the (unintelligible).
Ahmad: You were saying the messenger of the covenant and you said there is one covenant and so forth and...
Ahmad: He sent me a book describing what their point of view was of the covenant, of covenants.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Ahmad: like the... their distinction between 'Ahd (عهد), Mithaq (میثاق) and (unintelligible). There are 3 different words. I mean, I...
Dr. Khalifa: Are these Arabic, these are Arabic words?
Ahmad: Yes, they are Arabic words so I wrote them down.
Dr. Khalifa: 'Ahad? Ahmad: A H D, I wrote it down.
Dr. Khalifa: 'Ahd (عهد). 'Ahd (عهد). Ok. 'Ahd (عهد).
Ahmad: M I T... Dr. Khalifa: Mithaq (میثاق)? Ahmad: Mithaq (میثاق). Dr. Khalifa: Ok.
Ahmad: And she said "I S..."
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible) Ok. 'Ahd (عهد), Mithaq (میثاق) and (unintelligible). Ok. Ahmad: Yes.
Ahmad: (unintelligible) I, I, still we see that...
Dr. Khalifa: Is it a response to messenger of the covenant?
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, it's just a general...
Ahmad: Yeah, it's published by the Shia.
Dr. Khalifa: I'd like to see it. A woman: They've played it before.
Ahmad: Then, I'll Xerox is and...
Dr. Khalifa: Huh? A woman: They've played it before. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Ahmad: So, they don't see the word in the Quran. (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Ahmad: So, the righteousness (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: "I have also the Shia faith." Ahmad: Yes. They don't know. Dr. Khalifa: Sure!
Ahmad: Yes. You said (unintelligible)
Ahmad: What I wanted to say about that was maybe you could give what the entire covenant was. It was one covenant.
And therefore, what the full covenant was, as it is in the Quran, or whatever, (unintelligible). If you could give, it might help to...
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, well, you see, there's really no argument as far as this is concerned because the same word is used in 3:81 and in 33:7.
Dr. Khalifa: God said He made a covenant. It's a very strong word.
Ahmad: Yes. It's much stronger than agreements and arrangements. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Ahmad: In other words, I think we...
Dr. Khalifa: "Pledge" may be a better word.
Ahmad: Yes. Dr. Khalifa: Pledge.
Dr. Khalifa: The prophets pledged they'll fulfill their pledge.
Ahmad: Yes. While the Quran, I think, with other words also (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. For example, with Ibrahim, it's 'Ahd (عهد).
Ahmad: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: So with the prophets, it was Mithaq (میثاق).
A man: (unintelligible) covenant.
Dr. Khalifa: Mithaq (میثاق) is stronger.
Dr. Khalifa: Pardon?
A man: (unintelligible) covenant.
Dr. Khalifa: 1971. Yes.
Parivash: Rashad, I think...
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, it's right here in the footnote.
Parivash: When you show them, the Muslims, Sura 3 Aya, 81, and they say "this is Muhammad."
Dr. Khalifa: I know, yes.
Parivash: And when you show them the Bible that after Jesus comes another prophet. It's very clear.
Same thing, they say "this is Jesus."
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Yes. Parivash: Same thing.
A man: Even how could Jesus be son of God? How could he be it? Dr. Khalifa: It's the human.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: Either you give up as a messenger or you...
Dr. Khalifa: They want... A man: Cause then it's John.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: They want their cake and eat it too.
Footnote 33:7
A man: Yeah, but they force me back into saying, "this is John the Baptist."
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Dr. Khalifa: Anything to go to Hell. They'll try anything.
Page 419 at the bottom, 33:7. This verse refers to the covenant that is detailed in 3:81.
God took a covenant from the prophets that they shall support His Messenger of the Covenant who would come after them and is destined to unify their messages under the banner of worshiping God alone.
The specific identity of that messenger and details of incontrovertible supporting evidence are given in Appendices 2 and 26.
The Covenant was made before creation, and was finally fulfilled in Mecca Dec. 21, 1971 (Zul-Hijja 3, 1391).
It's amazing.
When you add 12, Zul-Hijja is the month. The number is 12 plus 3 is 15 plus 1391. You get... What you get?
Dr. Khalifa: 1406. 19x74
A man: Wow!
Dr. Khalifa: 1974 is when the miracle was finally materialized.
And Sura 74 is where the number 19 is mentioned.
You see the connections?
Pardon?
Yes.
It is somewhere. But look at the end of the footnote.
Page 419 at the bottom of the footnote.
In parentheses, Zul-Hijja 3, 1391.
This was the Tuesday during Hajj when I was in Mecca.
I mean, there is no mistake about the date.
I shared with you how God made me remember this day.
Zul-Hijja, the number of the month is 12.
The day is 3.
The year is 1391.
When you add 12 plus 3 plus 1391, you get 1406, which means, which equals 19 x 74.
Sura 74 is where the number 19 is mentioned.
1974 is the year when the miracle materialized, January 1974.
It was also Zul-Hijja, another year.
So, the connections are just very strong. God's proof is not subtle.
God's proof is very very overwhelming.
A man: One question.
A man: Prophets who have died are in another dimension, whereas (unintelligible) somebody. Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Dr. Khalifa: We answered this question yesterday. I guess you were not here.
Okay, we are thinking our limited, very limited existence here.
Dr. Khalifa: But the fact is, all the people who came to this world and departed are now existing in another world.
A man: Correct.
Dr. Khalifa: So, what are they doing?
Dr. Khalifa: You think they're doing more like this?
But those are souls.
And they have lots of, obviously have lots of activities going on.
And sooner or later we will join them.
Dr. Khalifa: So, there must be a lot of people over there, believers, who are...
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: This may be referring to the body. We're coming into a lot of understanding about this.
Let us share the verses that deal with this.
Because this is the best way to deal with it.
You know, this is something that I learned from that experience. And I didn't come to realize it until after the announcement.
So, we are now discussing it logically.
Ok, let's look at 3:169, is this what you said? 3:169.
Sura 3:169, on page what?
72. Wow!
I opened the book, by the way, and it came right there. So, this is a good sign, Alhamdu Lillah.
This means God wants us to discuss this matter now.
[3:169] Do not think that those who are killed in the cause of GOD are dead; they are alive at their Lord, being provided for.
No, the idol worshippers actually abuse this verse a lot.
And they go to the body of the saint, which is nothing, and they plead for help.
Now, this is the wrong understanding of the verse.
"They are alive at their Lord", they forget this expression, 'Inda Rabbihim (عِندَ رَبِّهِمْ), at their Lord.
It's very crucial to understand that. It's here.
So, like David was saying, they're unconscious, they are nothing, they are a piece of earth as far as the body is concerned.
But the persons themselves obviously exist somewhere, and I bore witness to this.
They're alive. That consciousness was very sharp, over there. It was very sharp. Not a word was spoken.
No, there was communications going on, at least when Abraham came in.
So, what does this say?
[3:169] Do not think...
This is for you and me, we should not think
[3:169] ...that those who are killed in the cause of GOD...
Now, this is referring to those who are killed in the cause of God, but it really is general. It includes all the righteous.
I have to show you another verse that, what I'm telling you now.
All the righteous, all the believers, and of course the prophets are among them, have this applying to them.
Don't think that they
[3:169] ...are dead; they are alive at their Lord, being provided for.
So, to complete the picture, let us look at this verse.
In Sura 4,
69. Wow! 169 and this is 69. 4:69.
So, if you add the digits, 4:69 adds to 19, also 3:169 adds to 19.
You see that?
This adds 3, Sura 3, verse 169 adds to 19, the digits.
And verse 4, verse 69, Sura 4, verse 69, also adds up to 19. Page 90.
I mean, God gives us this mathematical connections to tell us something.
Ok, 69 says, Equality of Believers.
[4:69] Those who obey GOD and the messenger belong with those blessed by GOD—the prophets, the saints, the martyrs, and the righteous. ...
So, all these are alive at their Lord, being provided for.
I think this is also a very significant expression, "being provided for."
So in other words, the believers... there is one more thing that I must share with you.
So now, we should not think of the believers and the righteous as dead, ok?
We're talking about the real persons, not the bodies.
The bodies are a piece of stone, and this is what the idol worshippers go to.
And these are utterly unaware, just like this carpet is unaware.
So, the one more thing that I want you to look at is in Sura 40, and the key word is (unintelligible).
I gave you the verse number in Sura 4.
40? It's 46.
Verse 40:46.
Page? 472.
Thank you.
472.
Verse 46 says, A Continuous Nightmare
[40:46] The Hell will be shown to them day and night, and on the Day of Resurrection: "Admit Pharaoh's people into the worst retribution."
Ok? So, these people are the disbelievers. This is now the other side of the coin.
Dr. Khalifa: The disbelievers see Hell every day, but they don't go in it until the Day of Resurrection.
Feroz: But isn't Hell not yet existing?
Dr. Khalifa: It doesn't exist yet, but, I mean, but they are told, they know. In other words, they say "you're gonna go to Hell, and this and that." A woman: In hell itself?
Dr. Khalifa: There's consciousness.
Huh?
Yes.
Yes. Oh yes, it is known.
That's it.
Yes. Exactly.
Exactly. And the people destined for Heaven are in their existence.
So, to answer Feroz's question "how will the prophets support the messengers of the covenant?"
Well, I'm gonna join them someday, and for all practical purposes, the time is very short.
So, what are they doing?
Feroz: Then, they will support you.
Dr. Khalifa: No, they did already. They bore witness.
Dr. Khalifa: It doesn't matter that...
Feroz: That kind of support. Just agree with your pledge there. Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: They know that we exist in the world somewhere, but they had to fulfill their covenant.
And that happened in Zul-Hijja, 1406...Zul-Hijja, 3, 1391.
So, God... in essence, God brought the messenger of the covenant, and "this is the messengers of the covenant. Do you agree? Do you fulfill your covenant?"
So, they came one by one. They said "yes."
And now they are talking with each other. Obviously, there's a Society up there, an Eternal Society.
A man: Because you (unintelligible)
A man: All prophets, even they're praying to God to give them support. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: And while they were there, (unintelligible)
A man: they left messages which would link up with the messenger of the covenant
A man: like Jesus spoke of the messenger of the covenant, or in the Old Testament, or the book of Malachi. Dr. Khalifa: Malachi.
A man: I mean, they left words behind to support...
Dr. Khalifa: Also, we have to think from their point of view.
Ok. From their point of view, I think God has done them a favor by letting them know that
"you guys delivered messages to the people, and now we're going to unify."
In other words, it's a piece of news to them also.
It's a favor to them.
So, "we're sending a messenger also to unify your messages in order to become aware of it", because
they are not aware of what's happening on earth.
They don't know who the president of the United States is, or who is ruling India at this time, and they don't give a damn.
They don't care.
The earth is a tiny, tiny thing. It is a very limited existence down here.
But it is a favor to them to let them know what is going on as far as their messages are concerned.
For example, if your company sends you somewhere to design a chemical plant, so you go there,
and you get on the drawing board, and you design the chemical plant, and you give the
plants to the people there, and then you go back to your headquarters, which is 10,000 miles away.
Then, someday the chairman of the board will call you and say "by the way, your plans that you drew for Guam were carried out, and the plant was established, and it is functioning very well now."
Of course, you'll be happy to know that.
This is exactly like that. You know, I just thought of an example on the spot.
But it's exactly like this.
They came down, they put the blueprints, they delivered messages, and it is nice to know
that this message will be unified in one, and that the majority of human beings will be given that one message, etc., etc.
It's like calling somebody in and saying "you know, remember those blueprints that you designed for Guam 10 years ago?
"The plant was built. It is now functioning. It is doing very well."
So, you say "thank you, sir."
Okay, Lisa.
Dr. Khalifa: I'm not gonna say anything interesting.
Lisa: Ok.
Dr. Khalifa: No worries.
Dr. Khalifa: God bless you.
Feroz: So I said, God doesn't mean Heaven or with God, like it's in this universe. Dr. Khalifa: No.
Dr. Khalifa: No, it's a limbo.
It is wonderful for the believers. It is awful for the disbelievers.
Cecilia, you know, people know... one of the best proofs that people know at the time of death, their destiny,
is that God tells us that the angels beat up the disbelievers on the faces and the rear ends.
Dr. Khalifa: Twice in the Quran.
Cecilia: Does the type of death have anything to do with it?
Dr. Khalifa: It's invisible to us. The answer is yes.
Cecilia: I know. I'm saying, you know, in terms of how we leave this world, the type of death that occurs. Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, let me, do you hear the question? Do you hear the question? Is the death different for the believers and disbelievers?
The answer is yes. Repeatedly in the Quran.
Death for the believer is a wonderful experience.
God says "the angels gently call the soul", and God Himself is telling the soul "come back to your Lord, happy and joyous and satisfied."
This is for the believer.
For the disbeliever, they beat him up and snatch the soul out.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, literally.
A man: That could be like a murder or...
Dr. Khalifa: No, no, no, the method doesn't make any difference.
A man: The type of death doesn't make any difference?
Dr. Khalifa: The type that we see doesn't make any difference, because the nervous system shuts off immediately anyway.
A man: In other words...
Dr. Khalifa: God's prophets to Israel were killed. Okay?
Dr. Khalifa: But that's the outside appearance. It doesn't mean anything. A man: It doesn't mean...
Dr. Khalifa: What happens in the other dimension, which is invisible to us, is the real thing, and it's totally different.
For the believer, it's a wonderful, beautiful experience.
For the disbelievers, it's an awful experience, because they cling to the body and they refuse to leave.
They don't wanna go.
And then they say "let go of your souls."
There's a verse that I want to remember, I wanna share with you.
I had it.
Dr. Khalifa: I had it, but I forgot, and I remember it again.
A man: Sorry. Does it mean the believer doesn't have a lingering, painful death?
Dr. Khalifa: No.
A man: (unintelligible) for the body.
Dr. Khalifa: As far as the body goes, yes, but without feeling it. We will not feel it.
A man: Meaning, slightly give it up, have to have a long suffering death.
Dr. Khalifa: Never. No suffering whatsoever.
Dr. Khalifa: For the believer, no suffering whatsoever, no matter what the method of death is on the outside.
Feroz: What about if he's under 40, can he have a lingering, painful death? Dr. Khalifa: No.
Dr. Khalifa: No. He'd be very happy.
The person under 40 immediately realizes that God is taking him, because he does not deserve
to go to Hell and live beyond 40 and go to Hell.
Feroz: Because I have had an auntie who died at 39, (unintelligible) quite a long process.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, this is like pains in this world. This will belong in the pains or tests or...
They are performing a function. When a child is born deformed and dies at the age of 14, that child performs a function,
Dr. Khalifa: and in return, he, the real person, goes to Heaven.
Feroz: The body can suffer, but the soul won't suffer. Dr. Khalifa: Right. That's right.
Dr. Khalifa: We're talking about the moment of death. I think that was David's question.
David: (unintelligible). I can see a healthy person, and the soul will suffer, and be miserable in life.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. The body doesn't mean a thing.
Remember there was a wave of reports on Eddie Murphy?
He's healthy, he's wealthy, he's successful, he's rich, but miserable.
Right?
Because happiness is not a property of the body.
Happiness is a function of the soul.
And he wrote, he said "something is missing."
He's got all the Rolls Royces, the Porsches, the Mercedes that he wants,
all the girls that he wants, all the money that he wants, mansions in New Jersey and California,
and he's miserable. He said something is missing.
So this is, it's well known now that material success doesn't have, has nothing to do with happiness.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Parivash: One day that, I think, someone argued with me about Martha.
Dr. Khalifa: About who?
Parivash: Martha. Dr. Khalifa: Martha.
Parivash: Yes. And I explained for her, she didn't believe, and I asked "OK, do you believe Jesus was (unintelligible)?"
And she said "of course." And I showed her these verses again.
Parivash: Jesus said "I told, I told..." Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
[5:117] "I told them only what You commanded me to say, that: 'You shall worship GOD, my Lord and your Lord.' ...
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
[5:117] ... I was a witness among them for as long as I lived with them. When You put me to death, You became the Watcher ...
[5:117] ... for as long as I lived with them. ...
Parivash: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Not after. Yes. Wonderful.
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Who created us?
Let's just say God number 1.
Because One God
Who created us? Let's say it's God number 1.
Ok. So, the question is "who created God?"
It's god number 2.
So, who created god number 2?
See, we're going along with an atheist who is asking this question.
He says "if God created you, who created God?"
We say "Ok. Let's give them numbers.
"God number 1 created us."
So, he says "Ok. Who created God number 1?"
"god number 2. And god number 3. god number 4."
"Who created number 4?" "god number 5."
"Who created god number 5?" "god number 6."
So, this will lead to what but Infinity of gods.
Mathematically, an infinity of gods equals One God.
There it is. There is one engine of God.
Dr. Khalifa: Now, we're talking about time, time frame. An infinity of gods equals one engine of God
Chester: So, (unintelligible) because there is infinite (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Yes.
Chester: So,... Dr. Khalifa: But
Dr. Khalifa: We're talking now about time, a time frame.
We're not talking about physical presence.
Also, we're trying to solve the problem of "if God created you, who created God?"
We're gonna end up with a (unintelligible) God.
Because now when you talk with an atheist who's asking this question, (unintelligible) step by step.
Say "I'm saying that God created us."
He says "Ok. Who created then number 1 God?"
Dr. Khalifa: Say "By number 2 god."
Chester: Rashad, I would say still... Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
A woman: I don't... I'm not even talking about (unintelligible) I understand it.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, you added the question which was good.
Chester: But I'm interested in the idea of God being physical form, number 1, and if God, there's no idea of concept of divinity for God.
Chester: So, Ok, then there's a saying that God had a birth.
Chester: And if He had a birth, then our, human concept would tell that He has a death.
Chester: For if there is just a birth concept, (unintelligible) death.
Dr. Khalifa: A birth from what?
Chester: Well, I don't know from what. Wait a minute!
Chester: Just saying that He is not infinite.
Chester: And He therefore... Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible) I'm not telling you that. Don't listen to me.
Chester: Ok.
Dr. Khalifa: You listen to Quran. A man: The Quran is saying.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. God is saying... Let's look at Sura 53, for example.
God says, He took Muhammad up to give him the Quran. And then, He came down
[53:9] Until He became as close as possible. [53:10] He then revealed to His servant (Muhammad) what was to be revealed.
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible). We have to believe that.
A woman: Can we not see that God is everything around us? (unintelligible)
A woman: (unintelligible) God.
A woman: which means God has... Chester: I don't deny, I don't deny at all
A woman: Ok, so, God has (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible) physical, right?
A woman: The (unintelligible)
Chester: I don't deny, I don't deny that Allah has (unintelligible) into being physical.
A woman: Ok. But what you are denying is that Allah has...
Chester: I'm not denying anything. A woman: Ok.
A woman: Ok. Listen. Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
A woman: No, I'm saying then Allah has the (unintelligible) within Itself to manifest Himself physical, physically.
Chester: I understand. A woman: Because He is Absolute.
A woman: So, why, so then that's what it is. He is manifesting Himself physically to us in the form that we will be able to handle.
A woman: Because what... He can...
Dr. Khalifa: No, wait a, well, let me back up a little bit, ok?
Dr. Khalifa: One of Satan's famous blasphemy is that God is a spirit.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: That He's devoid of physical powers.
Dr. Khalifa: You see the Christians doing this all the time, say "God is a spirit."
Dr. Khalifa: God is not a spirit.
God is the most physical of all physical things because He created the physical, He created this universe.
God is very, very, very, very infinite, very physical.
So, I think this is, you have trouble with this concept, initially.
Parivash: Rashad,... A man: (unintelligible)
Chester: I don't have trouble with the concept once it is explained by a person who I believe would know the answer.
That person would be yourself. If you explain it to me in a way that I understand it,
Chester: well, you understand more about the Quran than any other. Dr. Khalifa: I will try. I will try.
Dr. Khalifa: What I'm saying is that I'm not saying anything on my own.
Chester: I understand this.
Dr. Khalifa: All of us are referring to what God is telling us.
Dr. Khalifa: We have to compare this with what Satan is telling us.
Chester: And what Satan has dictated to me, and which I've been believing up until this very moment, Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Chester: was that God is, as you said, is in a spiritual form, has nothing to do with the physical at all. Dr. Khalifa: Right. Right.
Chester: Even though, I'm understanding, I understand, wrong now, but that He did bring into being a physical creation, Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Right.
Chester: even though He is some spiritual being, believing that He has that potential,
that ability because we're talking about continually the awesomeness of His power and His wisdom.
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, let's see how God tells us how physical He is, okay?
The Jinns, we do not see the Jinns. We do not see the angels. We do not see God.
And the Judeo-Christian concept as it exists today, and even the Muslim concept, is that these are spiritual beings, right?
So he's a spiritual being who carried the palace of the Queen of Sheba, 2,000 miles,
within a second, before Solomon blinked his eye. He carried the palace like this.
Now, how physical did it get?
Dr. Khalifa: Because it's not even like this, because the palace was carried intact.
Chester: Can we not say that God is power, to lift up those glasses from the floor, without touching them?
Chester: Would he have to necessarily have...
Dr. Khalifa: Well, some physical force will have to be exerted on these glasses to carry it from here to there.
Chester: That's what I've been saying.
Parivash: If God is a spirit, how can you enjoy when in Resurrection Day (unintelligible) to see Him and enjoy? Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Parivash: And another, another... Chester: So, we're talking about the dissolution of our physical bodies at that time,
Chester: and as we just went through a while ago, the interaction and the communication and identification of just spirit alone, without physical bodies.
Chester: Physical bodies stay here, but we can see each other and identify each other spiritually, spiritual beings, souls. Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, Chester, let us lay down the principle that we have a message from God.
God is telling straightforward things in this message, straightforward principles in it, straightforward information in the book.
Well, when we're growing up, Satan also is entitled to give us his message.
He's giving us certain information, and most of this information has to do with God and confusing the issue for us.
Dr. Khalifa: The way out of this dilemma is what?
Chester: The way out of the dilemma is to follow one and not the other. Dr. Khalifa: Exactly.
Dr. Khalifa: Exactly. The way out of dilemma is that you look at God's message, see what He's saying.
Whatever God is saying is true, even if it contradicts what we grew up learning,
because what we grew up learning is mostly Satan's education.
Parivash: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, so we look at Sura 53, we look at Sura 89, we look at Sura 7, 7:171, and 89:22, and 53:9.
All these are telling us that God is not physically here.
We also learn that God is very physical.
Parivash: One of them said seven heavens in the right hand.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, this here, yes, this is physical.
A man: Alright so, are we still, are we thinking of God in the same aspect
Like when we look at our own physical selves, when we talk about it being just, when we talk about energy?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, I'll get to you in just one second. I don't wanna interrupt Chester's flow of the subject.
Everything is physical in the world. You see the air, this air?
Dr. Khalifa: What, is air physical?
Chester: Okay, yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: You can take this volume of air and compress it, it becomes liquid, continue to compress it, it becomes solid.
Dr. Khalifa: Because what you're doing, you're bringing the molecules together.
Douglas: I think what we're asking is "will Allah manifest Itself as in piece of mass?"
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, a physical presence of God, a physical entity.
Dr. Khalifa: And this is what God is teaching us.
Edip: Rashad,...
Dr. Khalifa: God is a physical entity.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Go ahead. Edip: There's something confusing, I think, for our brothers, that they understand it from physics and we understand 104 elements.
Edip: I think this is confusing them, but God, how do you say it, we don't say God is physical elements, but I don't know (unintelligible) this kind of things.
Dr. Khalifa: We don't know what the physical nature of God is. Edip: Yes.
Edip: But we can see it. Dr. Khalifa: Feroz, what did you wanna say?
Feroz: I feel like we're stating God is a fusion of elements.
Dr. Khalifa: Right. Right. That's what Edip's saying. Edip: This is wrong.
Edip: Physical means you can feel, you can see, you can...
Chester: That's what I was asking, what I'm asking.
Edip: Yes, you can s. y this is God's and you can enjoy it.
Chester: But you cannot... what I was saying is that we cannot look upon it as we look upon what we call our physical selves.
Edip: We don't know, we don't know the fact in Hereafter how it will be.
For example, if the baby in the belly of his mother, if you try to tell this baby about this world, give him information about this world,
he cannot understand. He knows it's limited by darkness and very small things and there is heat. There's...
Edip: He doesn't know cold, what is cold. He doesn't know what is light. He doesn't know what is dark.
Parivash: What human look like. Dr. Khalifa: What the car looks like.
Douglas: When you say, when you tell me that Allah has so much energy that we cannot withstand His physical presence, Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Douglas: that's something physical. The energy is something physical. Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Very physical. Yes.
Douglas: I understand but I think when, you know, when you begin to try to explain to us that God will take on a physical presence, that means that He is... Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Not take on, God has a physical presence.
Douglas: Yes, but you were saying that He will manifest Himself to us so that we will be able to withstand His presence.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Douglas: That means that He has to do something outside of His self in order for us to see Him. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: No, God will physically come here.
Douglas: No, I'm not saying that God will physically Dr. Khalifa: Sura 89.
Douglas: come here (unintelligible). But it's gotta be some kind of shield or something. Dr. Khalifa: That's removed.
Douglas: No, that He has to put on for us to be with Him.
Dr. Khalifa: No, this is it. The shield will be removed. A woman: No, that's it.
Dr. Khalifa: This is when (unintelligible) Douglas: Will the shield be removed from us or from Him?
A woman: Yes, yes, from us.
Douglas: I'm asking Rashad. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Douglas: Will the shield be removed from us or removed from Him?
Dr. Khalifa: The shield right now is the distance.
Dr. Khalifa: The shield right now is distance.
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. Now, I have an appendix. This...
Douglas: I'm still not getting it.
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, we will, IN SHAA ALLAH.
I have an appendix that says "who is God?"
And it tells you how vast our universe is, 26 billion light years across, a billion galaxies, surrounded by 6 other greater universes.
Now, the outer limit of the first universe, if we are number 7, and the universe closest to God is number 1, mathematically is infinite.
But it is not infinite.
Mathematically, it's so huge, you cannot comprehend it.
Dr. Khalifa: There is no number in the universe that will tell us how long that circumference is.
Douglas: In our physical understanding, our limited mind. Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Right. Right.
Dr. Khalifa: Imagine the Earth, the solar system, 4 billion miles. Douglas: I can't imagine.
Dr. Khalifa: No, imagine the sun. Where is the sun?
Dr. Khalifa: Imagine the sun, because you see it every day.
Douglas: 93 million miles. Dr. Khalifa: 93.
Dr. Khalifa: 93 million miles.
Dr. Khalifa: 93 million miles. Only 8 light minutes. 8 minutes from us. Only 8 minutes.
Now, keep going for a hundred thousand years at the speed of light.
If you take off right now towards the sun at the speed of light, you'll get there in 8 minutes.
Now, keep going, not for a day or a month or a year, a hundred thousand years, we'll get to the edge of our galaxy.
Now, this galaxy, huge as it is, there are one billion of those.
And this is inside our universe, the smallest universe.
Let's call it universe number 7.
See, I'm glad you're laughing, okay?
Because we're beginning to comprehend the greatness of God.
We're talking about the physical entity of God.
This vast, vast, vast universe is the smallest of seven universes.
We call it universe number 7.
Universe number 6 is bigger. Number 5 is even bigger. Number 3 is bigger.
Number 3, 2, number 1. The circumference of number 1 is utterly infinite.
But it is not really infinite. We're using the word "infinite" to describe how huge it is.
Now, this infinite volume or size is within God's hand. That's what God is telling us.
So, how big is God?
That's the greatness of God.
This is the physical entity of God.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, Mã Shã Allãh.
A man: The hand is allegorical?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, the hand is allegorical. But you can think of me, for example, in my hand, and within my hand is this infinite...
A man: It shows the greatness of God.
Dr. Khalifa: So, if you can call the outer limit of the outer universe, infinite, what would you call God?
Dr. Khalifa: Huh?
A woman: Triple infinite.
Dr. Khalifa: Say it again?
Dr. Khalifa: Triple infinite.
So, there's no such thing, you know, but there are different infinities.
Dr. Khalifa: Are we grasping this? A man: Yeah, I'm hearing you.
A man: Now, as large as... This is what I'm trying to grasp now. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: Now, as large as Allah is... Dr. Khalifa: Right.
A man: He must then make Himself smaller...
Dr. Khalifa: No.
A man: ...to come to move into our presence? Dr. Khalifa: No, but we can...
Dr. Khalifa: The relative distance can be closer or farther.
We see it in Sura 53. Now, this is not... If I am theorizing, folks, don't listen to me, but I'm not theorizing.
Dr. Khalifa: I'm saying what God says in Sura 53.
Edip: He'll move closer.
Dr. Khalifa: God says, God took Muhammad from the planet earth, that He took him somewhere in the universe.
And then, God tells us He came closer, as close as possible.
Dr. Khalifa: If God came any closer, Muhammad will...
A man: So, are you saying that Allah is... Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, say it.
A man: He's limited in terms of what He has created?
A man: I mean, is He ruled by certain law, too?
A man: Is Allah being governed because he's saying that He (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: God is the lawmaker. God is the lawmaker.
A man: But He's also being governed by His own rules.
A man: He adheres to His own laws that He makes.
A man: Is that what you're saying? Dr. Khalifa: Well, of course.
Dr. Khalifa: He makes the laws and He abides by them. For example, God does not advocate sin.
Ok. This is the law. And God follows it. God does that.
Alright, so, God is telling us that He moved closer.
And God tells us in 89:22, that He will come to this world and that the heavens will fold like a book.
You hear about the stars crashing into each other in the Quran?
Why?
Because of this immense energy.
I mean, how big are the stars?
The sun, the sun is one of the dim stars. Did you know that?
We had a conference here at the University of Arizona across the street about the bright stars.
It's a conference about the bright stars.
You know what the definition of a bright star is?
This is science now.
A bright star is at least one million times as bright as our sun.
This is... Our sun is a very, very dim star.
Dr. Khalifa: Just look at the street out there. How many candles can you light to overcome it?
A woman: That's true.
Dr. Khalifa: If you put your finger in the sunlight, you see the shadow.
Dr. Khalifa: Now, light a number of candles to the rest of the shadows. A woman: To equal that shadow.
Dr. Khalifa: I mean,... A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: And that is one of the dim, that is one of the dim stars.
Dr. Khalifa: What happened?
A woman: Does that mean that we have a shield over us and when it's time for us to see Allah, you know, is the shield, because...
Dr. Khalifa: No, the shield is distance.
Dr. Khalifa: The shield is simply distance.
A man: Okay, can I ask you a question?
Dr. Khalifa: The shield, this body, the shield, the body as a shield is between us and the other dimension,
Dr. Khalifa: which is an invisible dimension,
Dr. Khalifa: where the jinns and the angels are. A man: When you say...
Dr. Khalifa: They see us, we don't see them.
Dr. Khalifa: Did you read that in the Quran?
A man: Yes.
A man: So, this is the veil that will be removed.
Dr. Khalifa: You know, folks, when we're through with this, when we're through with this,
when you stand and you say "Allahu Akbar", you will not say it the way you used to say it anymore.
A woman: It's the truth. We really know this. A man: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. When you say "God is Great", it's gonna have a whole different meaning, because we're coming
Dr. Khalifa: into this appreciation of (unintelligible). Yes.
A man: What I wanna say is this...
A man: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Just (unintelligible). Yes.
A man: When we say this that the only barrier is distance, Dr. Khalifa: Mã Shã Allãh
A man: but you're also saying that we cannot stand the Presence. Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Yes. Yes.
A man: So, upon death and moving out of this world... Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Right, you better be ready to be in that Presence.
A woman: Yeah. A woman: To be ready to handle it.
Dr. Khalifa: How do you be ready? How do you get ready?
You do the Five Prayers. You follow God's laws. You fast the month of Ramadan.
God is number one, not number one, the only One in your priorities.
And so this is how you...
Because every time you have anything to do with God, your soul is growing.
Your muscles are getting stronger.
You say "Subhan Allah", you're thinking about God, you're doing what we're doing now, your soul is growing.
Because your soul emanated from God.
And this is how it will grow, by serving God.
Now, I don't want any of us to freak out because we're discussing this, because all we're doing is reading what God is telling us. Ok?
It's just we have to be cool and quiet about it and see what God is telling us.
God's Grace is incomprehensible.
I wanna go through it again.
Because this will clarify the concept of infinity or lack of it.
If you take off right now at the speed of light, you will get to the Sun 93 million miles away.
New York is 3,000 miles.
And, you know, you think you came a long distance, right?
Ok. You take off 93 million miles. You get there in 8 minutes at the speed of light. You get to the Sun in 8 minutes.
Now, keep going, don't stop at the Sun.
For a month, then a year, 10 years, 100 years, 1,000 centuries.
Dr. Khalifa: Let us go for 100,000 years.
David: 100,000?!
Dr. Khalifa: 100,000 years at the speed of light.
Now, you left the Sun back there after 8 minutes of your takeoff.
David: Dear God. Dr. Khalifa: All right?
Dr. Khalifa: I'm glad you're laughing because this means you're understanding it.
After 100,000 years, David, you get to the border of our galaxy, the Milky Way.
Our galaxy.
Now, you know how far you have to go for the next one, the neighbor?
2 million light years to the next galaxy, just to get to the border of the next galaxy.
Because these galaxies are units within the universe, like this. This is a unit.
This is another unit.
So, from this unit to this unit, you travel 2 million, not 8 minutes, 2 million years at the speed of light.
No, it's one of the galaxies.
There are 1 billion of those.
So, now, think of our universe, which is, God says "this is the smallest universe, where the humans and the jinns exist."
26 billion light years. You have to travel 26 billion light years.
By the way, if you just count the stars that we have in our universe, it will take you
32 billion years, which is older than the universe.
Just count it, one second per star.
Okay, so this is now, we're talking now about a vast, vast universe, and this is the smallest of seven universes.
Now, think of the bigger one, the next one, which is even bigger.
How about the following one, which is even bigger?
And keep going bigger, and then you go to the first universe.
That is, you cannot, there is no number that will tell us what the circumference is, how long it is.
There is no number in the universe that describes that.
And that is within God's hand.
It's just to give us a picture of how Great God is.
So, if we can mathematically call the outer limit of the first universe, infinite, what can we call God?
So, figuratively speaking, we pull the rug from under Satan's feet, and we say "yes, figuratively, God is infinite."
Because of this incomprehensible Greatness.
But God is telling us there is a physical presence, and certain lines where you can move, God moves closer or farther.
And God is telling this in His word.
So, we are being alerted to what Satan is telling us.
Satan is very tricky. First, he wants to prevent us from ever coming to God.
But if we insist and we come to God, then he pushes to another extreme.
He said "okay, don't do just five prayers. Do twenty."
Dr. Khalifa: And he will give you things that will appeal to your religiousness, that you insisted on.
A woman: Rashad, I just want to bear witness to God for His immense Mercy and blessings upon all of us here.
A woman: And to just give thanks to Allah for giving us a messenger.
A woman: You are the messenger of God.
Dr. Khalifa: You're quoting, you're quoting the Quran.
Dr. Khalifa: God says "it's a blessing from God that He sends to among us a messenger." A woman: Nobody...
Dr. Khalifa: I'm talking as one of you.
A woman: Nobody could explain something so huge in understanding in such a manner that the human
mind in this dimension could understand it, I mean.
Dr. Khalifa: I'm really gratified when I see David's family. A woman: Alhamdu Lillah.
Dr. Khalifa: I'm gratified because it's really something he grasped it. He knew exactly what I'm talking about.
And these are sciences now.
It is no longer speculation.
Dr. Khalifa: You go take astronomy and this is what they tell you.
A woman: And we never took astronomy. We don't know physics. But you gave us physics, science, astronomy.
Dr. Khalifa: Time-life books. Time-life books. They have scenes of the universe.
I think I have a couple of them sitting there.
These are physical facts.
We travel at the speed of light. We have voids that go across the solar system.
Dr. Khalifa: We know exactly how far everything is and what the sizes are.
A man: I just received a book from (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Sorry.
A man: And it's called Space-Time Infinity. Dr. Khalifa: Right.
A man: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: So, I have, I just received it about maybe two weeks ago. But I haven't started reading it yet.
Dr. Khalifa: No, they're talking about infinity within God's hand.
A man: Within God's hand. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Within God's hand by millions of fractions, like very tight minute fraction.
Dr. Khalifa: Because they're talking only about the smallest universe, the smallest of seven universes.
A man: In Bombay, there is a show which has come from the United States.
It's being shown in the planetarium.
I haven't seen it but a good friend of mine saw it. And he said,
they have calculated and said that it is no longer a billion galaxies.
A man: They have estimated 3,000 billion galaxies. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: They stopped counting.
A man: Yes. They said, they're growing faster.
A man: It is probably growing faster than human population.
Dr. Khalifa: See, they counted the galaxies. We're talking about galaxies. We're not talking about solar systems or stars.
We're talking about galaxies.
Dr. Khalifa: So, when they reach 1 billion, you forget it.
Dr. Khalifa: "Hey, you know what, we're gonna stop here.
A man: The fact that we are so insignificant in size and the universe of seven heavens is so vast. Dr. Khalifa: Yes, God bless you. Yes.
A man: Is there any other purpose or is there a greater purpose outside of ourselves as far as the universe is concerned in terms of the (unintelligible)?
Dr. Khalifa: No.
Dr. Khalifa: The whole purpose is in 51:56.
Dr. Khalifa: That's the whole purpose.
Dr. Khalifa: There is one thing. There is one purpose and that is to redeem ourselves, to denounce our idolatry.
Did you see how difficult it is to talk the Mohammedans out of "La Elaha Ella Allah, Muhammad Rasulullah"?
You see the blasphemy of putting a tiny, tiny insignificant creature called Muhammad put his name next to God?
Dr. Khalifa: You see the blasphemy now?
A man: God is creating (unintelligible) for every human child that is born. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: What can you put next to God that will have some significance? You put ten galaxies?
"La Elaha Ella Allah, There are ten galaxies in the universe."
Dr. Khalifa: I mean, what is the comparison of Muhammad to ten galaxies?
A man: Okay. So, as vast, as vast and as great as the seven universes are and as vast as they are, the sole purpose of this creation was...
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, to be redeemed. A man: My God.
Dr. Khalifa: Right. God bless you, David.
A man: I think (unintelligible) there's more, more universes.
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Wonderful. Wonderful. Yes. Huh?
A man: There are some physical paradoxes which I just wanted to mention before being evaluated by you.
A man: One is that, you see, God has certain limitations.
One, He cannot create another being that has no birth and no death because when He creates it, it will have a birth.
A man: So, He cannot create another being.
Dr. Khalifa: You cannot say "God cannot."
A man: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: It's rather blasphemous to say "God cannot." A man: Ok.
A man: Mã Shã Allãh. Another blasphemous paradox which people have addressed to me is to say
A man: "He can't Dr. Khalifa: "create a rock that He cannot lift." A man: Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. The absurdities.
A man: You shouldn't think of it because it's not right.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, you must think of them, you must attack them and nullify them.
A man: No, but I can't answer him by saying that.
A man: Because the moment God creates, it has a beginning.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, exactly. That's what I call illegal questions.
Dr. Khalifa: They are questions that make themselves impossible.
A man: Paradox. Dr. Khalifa: Right, paradoxes.
A man: It's in reference to us, ourselves and the seven universes, when a larger comes toward us,
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, that's right.
A man: and we understand that each universe has its laws, and since our earth will change, will this affect all the seven universes?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, yes, yes, the seven universes will fold like a book.
Watch this.
When God comes to the seven universes,...
That's what God says in Sura 39.
What happens when you put a hydrogen bomb over Tucson? What will happen?
Huh?
It's gonna be a canyon.
It will be a grand canyon.
Dr. Khalifa: There will be a grand canyon here.
A man: So, the infinity equals one.
How to prove that to some atheist?
Dr. Khalifa: Pardon?
A man: You know, god number 2, 3, 4, infinity, infinity equals one.
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. An infinity of gods equals one infinite God.
Dr. Khalifa: It's mathematics.
(unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. We'll use Satan's terminology to defeat him.
A woman: One infinite God.
Dr. Khalifa: An infinity of gods equals One infinite God.
A man: Infinite gods, these ones, equal one.
Dr. Khalifa: Right. But we...
A man: It's still a paradox of Satan, circular motions.
Dr. Khalifa: That's fine, but this will shut him up.
There's no way we can go any further. Yes.
And because we have finite minds.
So, as he wants, he's trying to take advantage of our finite mind.
Dr. Khalifa: We're taking advantage of his finite mind and shutting him up for it to stop.
Edip: Rashad,...
Dr. Khalifa: But he cannot argue with this.
Edip: My question is this. I discuss with them a lot in Turkey.
There is a very different way to shut them up.
That is, I say "who created this material, this galaxy?"
They say "there is no being."
Edip: I say "it is the same for my God."
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Edip: They also have the same problem. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Edip: You have to say "who created this?" They would say Dr. Khalifa: "There was no begetting."
Edip: "I say the same thing for my God." Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Edip: "My God knows everything. Your god is material. And you have many gods."
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Edip: "And they have no conscience. They have no control. And you believe those stupid gods."
Edip: "But I believe that God controls everything."
"And you came up with a question that also you have this question."
Edip: "First, you give me an answer..."
A man: I think that what has happened is that, even for myself as well as Chandler, the alarm goes off.
when you begin speaking of God in a physical type of sense.
A man: People always have grown up to try to not fall into that trap of Jesus.
Dr. Khalifa: Exactly. See, when you, when you understand.
A man: The alarm goes off.
A man: And so, in terms of when we begin to try to grasp God in a physical sense, something human starts to come about.
Dr. Khalifa: Exactly. Mã Shã Allãh. A man: So, you know, the problem starts.
A man: In terms of we have to work it out. Dr. Khalifa: Mã Shã Allãh.
A man: I think we should try to attempt it.
Dr. Khalifa: You know, when we get a glimpse of God's Greatness, we realize the blasphemy of idol worship, the only unforgivable offense.
Now, this idiot, vice president of Islamic University of Medina, who says "is that all? God, that's all you have?"
I mean, can you imagine the blasphemy? How will he face God on the Day of Judgment?
When he knows what he should, what will we know?
Dr. Khalifa: "Is this all?" A woman: What else?
Dr. Khalifa: He wants to put next to God, Muhammad.
You can put Muhammad, Jesus, Abraham, Moses, you and me, and the whole solar system.
I mean, we're zero. It's nothing.
Mathematically, it's nothing.
I can say "La Elaha Ella Allah, ten galaxies are creatures of God."
"A million galaxies."
Put them next to God, where will they go?
If our whole universe is the smallest,...
I mean, look at the humiliation that God is doing to Satan.
Within the smallest universe, God gives him a tiny planet called Earth.
He said "this is yours, Satan, just see if you can run it."
A man: It might be a very good idea just to show them something like this colliding galaxies shown on a video.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: Then, it will really kill everybody.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. In fact, I do have this, the video tape of the mathematical miracle of the Quran.
I have, it's all in between...